Inventory of the Stephen and Mary Ann Livermore Papers 1842-1859
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Stephen and Mary Ann Livermore Papers 1842-1859 1842-1859
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2008.49
0.25
The papers are a collection of letters written to Mary Ann Brigham Livermore and Stephen G. Livermore from friends and family members throughout the New England region. Stephen Livermore originated out of Marlboro, Mass. Some of the papers are letters from him to Mary Ann before their marriage. Many of the letters are from family that live in Massachusetts towns such as Worcester, Boston, Millbury, Marlboro, Harvard, and Holden. Other locations include Dover, N.H., Wells River, Vt., and Avon, Conn. While they were still single Mary Ann lived primarily in Worcester and Stephen traveled around the area searching for work. They spent their early married years in Springfield, Mass. from 1849-1852. Their most recent letters show that they later moved to Dayton, Ohio.
Livermore, Stephen G.; Livermore, Mary Ann Brigham arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 05/19/2008.
Biographical Note
Information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Stephen G. Livermore.
Scope and Contents
The papers are a collection of letters written to Mary Ann Brigham Livermore and Stephen G. Livermore from friends and family members throughout the New England region. Stephen Livermore originated out of Marlboro, Mass. Some of the papers are letters from him to Mary Ann before their marriage. Many of the letters are from family that live in Massachusetts towns such as Worcester, Boston, Millbury, Marlboro, Harvard, and Holden. Other locations include Dover, N.H., Wells River, Vt., and Avon, Conn. While they were still single Mary Ann lived primarily in Worcester and Stephen traveled around the area searching for work. They spent their early married years in Springfield, Mass. from 1849-1852. Their most recent letters show that they later moved to Dayton, Ohio.
Arrangement of Materials
Letters are arranged in chronological order.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Letters (correspondence)
Geographic Name:
Connecticut--History--19th century.; Massachusetts--History--19th century.; Massachusetts--Social life and customs; Massachusetts--Social life and customs--19th century.; New Hampshire--History--19th Century.; New Hampshire--Social life and customs--19th century.; New Hampshire--Social life and customs.; Vermont--History--19th century.
Topical Term:
Agriculture--Massachusetts--History--19th century.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Letters, 1842; id29985 (Folder 1)
  - Letter, id29984 (Folder 1)
    - Letter, id29986 (Folder 1)
  - Letter, id30493 (Folder 1)
  - Letter, id30496 (Folder 1)
  - Letter, id30497 (Folder 1)
  - Letter, id30776 (Folder 1)
  - Letter, id30777 (Folder 1)
- Letters, 1845; id30778 (Folder 2)
  - Letter, id30779 (Folder 2)
  - Letter, id30782 (Folder 2)
- Letters, 1846; id30784 (Folder 3)
  - Letter, id30786 (Folder 3)
  - Letter, id30787 (Folder 3)
  - Letter, id30788 (Folder 3)
- Letters, 1848; id30789 (Folder 4)
  - Letter, id30790 (Folder 4)
  - Letter, id30791 (Folder 4)
- Letters, 1849; id30793 (Folder 5)
  - Letter, id30797 (Folder 5)
  - Letter, id30798 (Folder 5)
  - Letter, id30799 (Folder 5)
  - Letter, id30800 (Folder 5)
  - Letter, id30801 (Folder 5)
  - Letter, id30802 (Folder 5)
  - Letter, id30803 (Folder 5)
- Letters, 1850 (January-May); id30804 (Folder 6)
  - Letter, id30805 (Folder 6)
  - Letter, id30806 (Folder 6)
  - Letter, id30807 (Folder 6)
  - Letter, id30808 (Folder 6)
  - Letter, id30809 (Folder 6)
  - Letter, id30810 (Folder 6)
- Letters, 1850 (June-December); id30811 (Folder 7)
  - Letter, id30812 (Folder 7)
  - Letter, id30813 (Folder 7)
  - Letter, id30814 (Folder 7)
  - Letter, id30815 (Folder 7)
  - Letter, id30816 (Folder 7)
  - Letter, id30817 (Folder 7)
- Letters, 1851; id30818 (Folder 8)
  - Letter, id30819 (Folder 8)
  - Letter, id30820 (Folder 8)
  - Letter, id30822 (Folder 8)
  - Letter, id30824 (Folder 8)
  - Letter, id30826 (Folder 8)
- Letters, 1852; id30828 (Folder 9)
  - Letter, id30829 (Folder 9)
  - Letter, id30831 (Folder 9)
  - Letter, id30832 (Folder 9)
- Letters, 1855; id30833 (Folder 10)
  - Letter, id30834 (Folder 10)
  - Letter, id30835 (Folder 10)
- Letters, 1856-1857; id30836 (Folder 11)
  - Letter, id30837 (Folder 11)
  - Letter, id30838 (Folder 11)
  - Letter, id30839 (Folder 11)
- Letters, 1858; id30840 (Folder 12)
  - Letter, id30841 (Folder 12)
  - Letter, id30842 (Folder 12)
  - Letter, id30843 (Folder 12)
- Letters, 1859; id30844 (Folder 13)
  - Letter, id30845 (Folder 13)
  - Letter, id30846 (Folder 13)
  - Letter, id30847 (Folder 13)